<resources>
    <string name="app_name">oopsiesMeasurement</string>
    <string name="educational_button">Educational</string>
    <string name="fun_facts_button">Fun Facts</string>
    <string name="settings_button">Settings</string>
    <string name="phenomena_and_illusions_button">Phenomena and Illusions</string>
    <string name="length_mass_and_time_button">Length, mass and time</string>
    <string name="estimating_quantities_button">Estimating Quantities</string>
    <string name="heat_and_temperature_button">Heat and Temperature</string>
    <string name="phenomena_illusions_title">Phenomena and Illusions</string>
    <string name="about_us_appTitle">OOPsies\nMeasurement\nProject</string>
    <string name="about_us_textView0">A group of student\'s attempt on creating an app</string>
    <string name="about_us_textView2">Our Team</string>
    <string name="about_us_textView3">Daryl Kardil Kelabit</string>
    <string name="about_us_textView4">Adrian Lau Hui Yi</string>
    <string name="about_us_textView5">Abdullah Al-Hisyam</string>
    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="source_code">Source Code</string>
    <string name="textView1">We would like to hear your valuable suggestions. Please fill in the feedback form in the settings page.</string>
    <string name="phenomenon_illusions_intro">\nWhat is phenomenon?</string>
    <string name="phenomenon_illusions_definition">\nDefinition:\nA phenomenon (plural: phenomena) is an observable fact or event.\n\n</string>
    <string name="text_aurora">This is a picture of an aurora. An aurora is a natural light display in the Earth\'s sky, predominantly in high-latitude regions like the Arctic and Antarctic. Since they are an observable occurrence and event, therefore it is an phenomenon.\n\n</string>
    <string name="text_explanation">Every event in the universe, from your next breath to a star exploding, is an interaction of matter and energy, so physics is really a part of all the other scientific subjects rather than a separate one.\n\n</string>
    <string name="text_star_explode">This is an animation of a star exploding.</string>
    <string name="buttonNext">Next</string>
    <string name="buttonBack">Back</string>
    <string name="buttonHome">Home</string>
    <string name="buttonReturn">Return</string>
    <string name="phenomena_illusions_secondary_title">Launching a Rocket</string>
    <string name="text_rocket_launch">SpaceX rocket launch\n\n</string>
    <string name="rocket_explanation">Light from the engines of a rocket can be seen immediately by the distance spectators as the rocket begins to rise from the launch pad. The speed increases every second as it went up high into the sky. The rocket is divided into parts called stages. Every stage has a fuel tank and rocket engines. When fuel in a stage is used up, the rocked will then detach from the others, hence enables the next stage to use its rocket engines and fuel, to propel the rocket further more into the sky. After all stages are completed, only one small stage is left, which is where the cockpit is located. Thus, it is left orbiting around the Earth in space or set off across the Solar System.\n\n</string>
    <string name="illusion_secondary_title">What are illusions?</string>
    <string name="illusion_definition">Definition: An illusion is a distortion of senses, which can reveal how the human brain normally organizes and interprets sensory stimulation.\n\n</string>
    <string name="optical_illusion_explanation">This is a still image depicting an optical illusion.\n\n</string>
    <string name="illusion_explanation">Illusion can occur with any of the human senses, but optical illusions are the best-known and understood because visual often dominates the other senses.\n\nThere are auditory illusion such as the Shepard tone, tactile illusion such as phantom limb, temporal illusion which means the distortion in the perception of time etc.</string>
    <string name="heat_temp_title">Heat and Temperature</string>
    <string name="heat_temp_secondary_title">\nWhat is temperature?</string>
    <string name="heat_temp_definition">\nDefinition: Temperature is a physical quantity that expresses hot and cold/ It is the manifestation of thermal energy, presented in all matter, which is the source of the occurrence of heat, a flow of energy, when a body is in contact with another that is colder or hotter.\n\n</string>
    <string name="image_thermometer">A thermometer.</string>
    <string name="text_temperature_explanation">\nThe temperature of a substance is measured on a scale that has two fixed points. The most widely used temperature scale is the Celsius scale. Its two fixed points are 0 degree Celsius which is the melting point of ice or freezing point of water, and 100 degree Celsius which is the boiling point of water. A thermometer compares the temperature of the substance in which the bulb is immersed with the freezing point and boiling point of water. It compares the hotness or coldness of a substance.\n\nThe lowest possible temperature, known as absolute zero, is -273 degree Celsius. Temperatures can go as high as millions of degrees Celsius.\n\n</string>
    <string name="estimating_quantities_title">Estimating Quantities</string>
    <string name="estimating_quantities_secondary_title">\nWhy do we do estimation?\n</string>
    <string name="text_estimation">Can you estimate the total number of candies inside this jar?</string>
    <string name="text_estimation_explanation">\n\nAt the beginning of an investigation, it may be useful to estimate the quantities that are going to be used or the time that is going to be taken for certain observations. At this stage of the investigation, accuracy is not essential just yet.\n\n</string>
    <string name="length_mass_time_title">Length, Mass, and Time</string>
    <string name="length_mass_time_secondary_title">\nIntroduction</string>
    <string name="length_mass_time_intro">There are three things being measured in many investigations are length, mass, and time. Any measurement is made in units. For example, a common unit of length is the centimetre. There is an international system of units that is used by scientist throughout the world. This is known as the SI units.\n\n</string>
    <string name="si_units_explanation">Visual representation of the SI units.</string>
    <string name="measuring_length_title">\n\nMeasuring Length</string>
    <string name="measuring_length_content">\nThe standard SI unit of length is metre. Its symbol is m, and as with all symbols for SI units, no full stop is placed after it. Metre is divided into smaller units for measuring all small lengths or distances, and large numbers of metres are made into bigger units to measure long lengths or distances.\n\nFor example, 1 kilometre is 1000 m; 1 centimetre is 0.01 m; 1 millimetre is 0.001 m and so on.\n\n</string>
    <string name="accuracy_title">\nAccuracy of Measurements</string>
    <string name="accuracy_intro">\n\nAccuracy depends on the measuring instrument as of how well it has been constructed. A stopwatch that only measures time by seconds cannot be used to time events to a tenth of a second.\n\n</string>
    <string name="text_tools">Some examples of measuring instruments.</string>
    <string name="tools_explanation">\n\nYour accuracy also depends on how well you use the measuring instrument. Care in setting up the device is needed. For example, you must place a ruler accurately when measuring length, reset a stopwatch before repeating a timing and make sure that a balance is set at zero before a mass is put on it. If a balance is used with a scale that is read by looking at the position of a pointer, your eye should be placed directly in front of the pointer.\n\n</string>
    <string name="liquid_thermometer">\nThe liquids in thermometers\n</string>
    <string name="text_alcohol_mercury">Two liquids are commonly found in a thermometer. They are alcohol and mercury.\n\n</string>
    <string name="liquid_explanation">Mercury has a freezing point of -39 degree Celsius and a boiling point of 360 degree Celsius while alcohol has a freezing point of -112 degree Celsius and a boiling point of 78 degree Celsius.\n\nIf the bulb of the thermometer is placed in a hot substance, the liquid inside expands and spreads up inside the thermometer tube. The level it reaches depends on the hotness of the substance, and the temperature can be read from the scale. If the bulb is then placed in acold substance, the liquid inside contracts back down the tube. The level at which it settles depends on the coldness, and again the temperature is read from the scale.</string>
    <string name="nmeasuring_time_title">\nMeasuring Time</string>
    <string name="measuring_time_content">\nThe standard SI unit of time is second with the symbol s. Other units includes day, hour, minute, second, millisecond, and more. For example, 1 day is 86,400 seconds, or 1,400 minutes, or 24 hours; 1 hour is 3,600 seconds or 60 minutes; 1 millisecond is 0.001 second and so on.\n</string>
    <string name="text_stopwatch">Stopwatch for measuring time</string>

</resources>